<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <description></description>
        <link>http://www.wrinq.com/</link>
        <author>akshatjiwan@gmail.com (Akshat Jiwan Sharma)</author>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 12:54:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ Simple things you can do to increase market value of your property]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/blogthe-simplest-things-that-you-can-do-to-increase-market-value-of-your-property-instantaneously</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 07:16:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>As a landlord one of things you are responsible for is the marketing of your property. While the old adage "Location, location,location" is  still one of most important factors that prospective tenants take into account when choosing a property, sadly it is also the something that you can do nothing about. You can't really change the location of your property. So how do you stay relevant in the market? How do you attract better tenants to your property?</p><p>First focus on the basics. Make sure that your property is well maintained. Fix any broken pipes, repair any cracks and make sure that your property is in tip top condition. If you are renting furnished homes spend a few days decorating your offering according to the tastes of the tenants that you are trying to attract. Remember that if you can appeal to their likes you are one step closer to closing the deal.</p>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What we are doing with wrinq?]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/blogwhat-we-are-doing-with-wrinq</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 07:32:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We started wrinq with a very clear purpose of simplifying rent collection and bookkeeping for landlords. We felt that most people don't take their <a href="/blog/why-would-you-want-to-streamline-your-property-rental-business/">property rental business</a> seriously. They don't get their tenants verified. They don't issue rent slips. They don't even keep books. Their rental business is in a total disarray. Personally I feel very strongly about this issue as I have seen first hand the importance of <a href="/blog/the-importance-of-keeping-your-rental-accounts">keeping your rental accounts</a>. </p><p>So we talked to several landlords and letting agents and pitched to them our idea. We would make a product that would allow them to collect their rent via paypal. Their tenants need not have a paypal account just a credit card with which they can pay their rent. Every month an email will be sent to the tenant as a reminder. On the payment of the rent a rent slip would be mailed to them. The landlord will have the record of all of their collections in one place. Wrinq could be used from smart phone. You won't even need to download any additional app to use it. Your default email application will be enough.  Simple and easy.</p>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The gap between property search engines and real estate agents]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/blogthe-gap-between-property-search-engines-and-real-estate-agents</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 14:57:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I spend time with a lot of real estate agents. A few of them are my friends and often over lunch our conversation turns to property search engines. They don't deny their usefulness they even like it but all of them are unequivocal in their opinion that selling property is still a boots on the ground business. </p><p>They say that while real estate search engines are good for getting new clients in, the core of the business still comes from the people they know, the people they have worked with and the people that have recommended them. It so happens that an agent helps Mrs. kitty to move into a new home and Mrs kitty, quite satisfied with her accommodation,recommends the agent to her friend who is also looking for a new house and the agent knows a Mrs Sheldon who is looking for a new tenant and he sets a meeting between two. </p>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Basic bookkeeping for landlords]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/blogbasic-bookkeeping-for-landlords</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 09:28:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We've already talked about the importance of <a href="/blog/the-importance-of-keeping-your-rental-accounts">keeping rental accounts</a> by the landlords. But we never really discussed what goes into a record book. A record book, a ledger or an account whatever you may call it is basically a log of financial transactions between a landlord and a tenant. A tenant agrees to pay a certain sum of money in exchange of utilizing your property for living. The absolute minimum that every record book should contain therefore is a log of payments made by the tenant to you. Suppose your tenant pays you $1275 for the month of June. Here is what a record book may look like:-</p><pre><code>Rent    Due Date    Paid On        Tenant Name$1275    3 Jun 2013    5 Jun 2013    Margret Blaine</code></pre>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Landlord's due diligence]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/bloglandlords-due-diligence</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 18:15:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In many cases the disputes between the landlord and the tenant areover matters that can be easily resolved (or even avoided all together) by the presence of a <a href="/blog/the-importance-of-a-rent-contract/">valid contract</a>. Matters likely to cause disputes like-:</p><ol><li>Who bears the cost of repairs?</li><li>How the water/electricity bill is to be split?</li><li>When and by how much the rent will be increased? </li></ol>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The other benifits of rent slips]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/blogthe-other-benifits-of-rent-slips</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 14:26:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I already talked about <a href="http://www.wrinq.com/blog/the-importance-of-keeping-your-rental-accounts">the importance of keeping your rental accounts</a> before. Issuing timely rental slips forms an important part of keeping the accounts by any landlord. But there is more to the significance of rental slips than it just being a log of your earnings.  </p><h3>Importance of rental slips for the tenants</h3>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Would you like to have sherlock holmes as your tenant?]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/blogwould-you-like-to-have-sherlock-holmes-as-your-tenant</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 12:06:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>"Yes please!"</strong></p><p>Err.. that was quick.  I suppose that lately you've been watching re-runs of Sherlock and your fascination for our enigmatic detective is at an all time high. Not only would you like to have him in your house you would gladly assume the role of Mrs. Hudson and gratify Holmes with a cup of tea every morning while he sets your first floor on fire. </p>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The importance of a rent contract]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/blogthe-importance-of-a-rent-contract</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 08:17:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Disputes between landlords and tenants are,unfortunately,quite common. They can arise due to innumerable reasons. The tenant may not agree to an increase in rent after a certain period. The landlord may interfere with the basic amenities or refuse repairs. You could go on forever and never run out of reasons that may lead to a dispute. Most of the disputes however can be avoided easily by having rent contract in place. So what's a contract? </p><blockquote><p>A contract is an agreement enforceable by the law. </p></blockquote>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The importance of keeping your rental accounts]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/blogthe-importance-of-keeping-your-rental-accounts</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 03:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Benjamin Franklin wrote in his autobiography some 200 years ago : </p><blockquote><p>I mention it as a lesson to those young men  who  may be  employ'd  in managing  affairs  for others,  that  they should  always  render accounts,  and  make  remittances, with great clearness and  punctuality. The character of observing  such a conduct is the  most powerful of all recommendations to new employments and increase of business.</p></blockquote>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's about  convenience]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/blogits-about--convenience</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 03:16:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>A business sells not just the product but the convenience that the use of it's product brings to the users. You are in the business of renting your property. When a potential tenant comes to looking for a place to say she/he evaluates the benefits that renting your house will bring. </p><p>Is it close to the market? </p>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why would you want to "Streamline your property rental business"?]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/blogwhy-would-you-want-to-streamline-your-property-rental-business</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 08:58:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>One recurring sentence you might have read throughout our website is </p><blockquote><p>Streamline your rental property business </p></blockquote>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Set and forget]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/blogset-and-forget</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 13:05:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p> wrinq is designed to keep your engagement with the application as low as possible.</p><p>Why would we want to do that? </p>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What does "A small transaction fee" mean?]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/bloga-small-transaction-fee</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 07:14:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>So you have read about wrinq and found that you can probably use it to manage your rent. There is just one tiny problem. You don't know what it costs. The phrase "a small transaction" fee does not inspire much confidence in you. I can probably guess what you are thinking right now. </p><p>"A small transaction fee eh? A good way to say I will charge you as much as I want" </p>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is wrinq all about?]]></title>
            <link>http://www.wrinq.com/blogwhat-is-wrinq-all-about</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 13:25:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The idea behind wrinq is simple. It is built to help you collect your rent on time from your tenants. That is all there is to it. But the question is why would you need a an online service to do that for you? Is it not much simpler to do it all yourself? </p><p>It is simpler I agree but at times it can be <a href="/blog/what-is-wrinq-all-about">inconvenient</a>. Suppose you collect your rent at 5th of every month. And on 6th you bump into your tenant at the park. After exchanging civilities you summon up strength to suggest to your tenant that he is overdue.</p>]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Akshat Jiwan Sharma</name>
            </author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>